Hello and welcome in, my name is Drumroll Tony, I'm a streamer on Twitch, musician and
music teacher living in Seattle.
We're so close friends, we're less than 500 people away from hitting 100,000 subscribers
on the channel.
I invite you to help me hit that goal.
Please and thank you.
If you've not subscribed yet, please click that button.
This is awesome.
It feels good.
I'm excited to keep this going.
All right, we're going to be checking out some video game music.
This is a recommended video for one of my Patreon members, and this is going to be Genshin
Impact, Scaramouche, The Prodigal, all phases, some boss music here, and it looks long.
In the description here we have the introduction, phase one, phase two before the cutscene, and
then phase two.
So yeah, let's check it out.
All right, we're going to dig in here.
I can see, I'm just scrubbing along here.
I can see the introduction goes all the way up to the minute 37 mark.
We'll try to get that and see what's going on here.
Okay.
That's pretty good.
Cool little woodwind melody that came in there, but hold on.
We got to talk about, it's probably a prepared piano.
We're getting this mysterious kind of dark clock sounding, this like low end strike.
We're striking the string.
You know, sometimes we get to do fun stuff with the piano, mess it all up and play on
it in different ways.
Pretty good.
The little responses and the tremolos and the strings, very, very, very creepy.
Let's go back a couple seconds here and get into this woodwind melody.
This is the first one we're going to be playing.
The low brass is in tune, so good.
We'll give it a try.
What an amazing introduction.
Okay.
The obvious stuff we talked about that clock, that mysterious clock
sound on the prepared piano that's dead constant the whole time.
And we had this really great shift between the strings and the woodwinds
playing our whatever, whatever, I'm a lot of phrase there, but this is the
transitions and I was orchestrated and written between the players.
Really, really great.
Sounds like kind of a intimate, intimate, uh, pit setting, like front, like down
in the musical down, down what's in the pit.
Oh, very, very, very cool.
We'd love to play something like this.
Okay.
Let's go back a couple seconds here and grab, I guess we're into the phase one.
Let's get this.
Wow.
Okay.
Uh, check it that they could, that they could, that we have this
big, uh, threes triplet, uh, foundation.
So are they real shakers or the digital?
Cause I know a lot of people that I've played with, I can play
with the shakers and it sounds very like little eggs.
Sounds very, very good.
Did you hear the little intimate triangle work in the background?
People give triangle players a lot of crap, but you shouldn't.
It's a delicate instrument.
Very cool.
And in case you didn't know, it's not like it's this one person that only
plays a triangle percussionist play like everything in the concert percussion
realm, which you do, you know what sometime we should do if you've done that.
Anyway, let's go back five and keep going.
Cause it sounds like this is about to get real big here.
Wow.
Okay.
Uh, it almost felt like a metric modulation.
It wasn't cause I was getting, I was getting confused because when we started
with our string involvement, where it was like still deep and brooding and evil
sounding, and then the bait that digital, we'd like this really smooth transition
from like string and woodwinds and then incorporated digital stuff.
Uh, very, very cool.
Great ideas.
But then that bonk, I was like, wait, is this like a displaced, like dotted
eighth rhythm or maybe like a quarter of a triple thing where we go on somewhere
new and then it came in and I feel like we had a one, two, three, one, two,
three, one, two, three, one, two, three, buckle, buckle, but we had some, that
kind of combination going on for the meter.
I'm not totally sure.
Cause we just heard it.
There was a lot of things to listen to and there's like epic choir stuff happening.
This is amazing.
So far.
interesting boogadat boogadat boogadat doogadat doogadat doogadat is our main kind of formulation
of rhythmic melody that going on there um evil i say evil all the time i don't think
everything's evil but um those voices without effects just sound big and dark so i don't
know what kind of boss we're fighting in this game at this point but uh i'd probably not
want to be the boss just so i can keep listening to the music all right we're going back five
here we go
that was cool we always ask for it's like every day i'm like hey what do you do what
do you want to create stuff that's new take away a layer and build it back up it's good
it's uh it's like the solid you know it's solid goal right there you'll you'll achieve
it every time great use of it i really like those big triplets that we came out of though
that was fun we'll go back five and grab that again
even in there there's still layers going on the predominant voice obviously is the big
whoa that sound in the vocal layer but we have strings and low brass supporting all
of that um it's interesting to think about how loud this is right we've arrived and we
just kind of stayed at this dynamic level so clearly a lot of stuff is happening with
what's going on with how they program these to work with how you're fighting the boss
so that that alone always interests me quite a bit like how video game music works but
um obviously we're just kind of the linear straight playthrough so we're not gonna have
too much deviation but still it's big and just uh your ears are getting you're getting
run in here okay so that was phase one now we're at phase two before the cut scene
here we go
very cool
all right so we got to talk about the combination of three
so you're probably feeling it now but in reality we're still because all that can still be
divided down to right here where everything in this piece has been super slow the beginning
was a little slower but all phase one we still pulled right here at this tempo and technically
we're still there but we've just added a bunch of stuff on top to augment it but just know
just know the root foundations are still present we just got these like triplet grooves going
on i'm just gonna go back like right here
very interesting use of like the you know the movie theater bass drops so that kind
of stuff we have that with like but it's like super palsy and like fuzzy and buzzy um we
do still have remember the shaker the egg shaker triplet kind of figure that's still
present now but definitely in a way more digital environment so that's fun how that has existed
across this this cutscene bar line though all right back five let's keep going
before we go any further the church organ part was pretty cool because that like um
harmonically was like what kept us together thinking in bomb that's where our harmonic
structure is even though we have boom doom to goo goo goo goo goo and all this weird like
digital stuff happening the organ is definitely our like tonal center so that was pretty fun
this too all right so before the drop hits we got to talk about a different tempo and
then we have this is our focus bump bump oh oh four and talk about all the time it's bossa
nova dude that's straight up bossa nova but we're using it in a very different form here
so it doesn't sound like brazilian music whatsoever but that's where those rhythms came from all
right very cool so the whole time like if you're someone that's an orchestrator you're
a young composer you're like thinking about how do i layer stuff this is how you layer
stuff you keep things right boom right here and you add everything on top of that with
whatever is going on there's like a million strings there's all the digital like bass
drop stuff we have the there's that violin part that's coming in and jamming out there
and then you have your choir just obviously uh laying it in your ears letting you know
where you're at but it's it's all there we're just really literally over one chord and we
just kind of build on the extensions of that chord sounds great though like there's nothing
wrong with that that definitely sounds amazing back five let's keep going
cool
so melodically we have a lot of different intervals going on and compared to um we could
we could say we're in a mode versus what we were before where basically everything kind
of function around one two flat three which is very minorish uh i'm not gonna sing that
right because i i'm a drummer first and foremost in the bass player not a vocalist but point
me now we're seeing more of like uh phrygian ish with a lot of flat two stuff happening
that won't really if if you don't care about like scale stuff that stuff doesn't really
mean anything but just know that the scale composition is similar but we've added a couple
things in so we're going through some modes to give it that you know like that sound you're
like oh i might have heard that like in like a movie like it sounds like you know a different
part of the world yes it does because uh expected scale systems differ or just different folks
use different things okay so it's very it's very it's very cool it's all on purpose very
good it's very good
the reason i made that face because then suddenly we went from what i just mentioned a second
ago and now we're way more traditional the way chords are functioning
and suddenly it has a lot more like i don't know late classical baroque stuff going on
there's someone smarter than me that has way better aural uh identifiable identify skills
that have to do that because i just can't but it's funny how quickly that shifted so
definitely enjoyable to listen to though
i'm sorry to keep stop so much but there's so much cool stuff to talk about uh the little
violin line that button yeah that was pretty sick but what's really different here is the
do going on underneath that after we just came out of all that other stuff that is a
huge shift in the lower end percussion layer there that's pretty wild
okay
So when someone says, well, what kind of, you know, what kind of piece is this?
You just say, yes, it's like, how many styles are we going to hear back to back?
That's pretty fun.
It is like completely like, it's interesting when you study music, like in a traditional
standpoint, this is very not traditional, right?
We don't normally like jump thousands of miles of musical influence, like global influence,
but now we do.
I mean, not saying it's bad, not saying it's good.
I'm just saying it's cool.
And like, it's a fun thing to experience in your headset.
Like in a matter of seconds, you're like, wow, we've totally, we're just jumping over
time periods.
We're jumping across the world.
Very, very cool.
It's just different.
All right.
Let's take it out.
What a great piece of music.
The end, the unison lines there between voice and brass and strings, and then setting it
home with our percussion hits.
Outstanding stuff.
I would love to know if any of you that watch these videos are composition majors or you're
working on writing music or what kind of stuff you do.
Maybe you're want to be, you know, be writing music for video games down the road or maybe
cinematic stuff.
I would love to know if any of you are checking these vids out because I would love to hear
your stuff.
Sorry.
I'm not, now I'm like in gamer geek mode and I just want to hear that stuff.
So let me know.
My name is drumroll Tony.
Make sure to catch me on them live.
We can talk about your favorite video game music or just music in general.
You can find the link to my Twitch channel in the video description below, as well as
my discord.
If you'd like to support the channel, my patron information is down there.
Thank you so much for watching.
If you liked this video, please click that thumbs up button.
I appreciate you take it easy.
Bye bye.