Alrighty, ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls, welcome back to another Genshin Impact reaction
video.
This is going to be a pretty short one.
We are in the kind of dry spell before version 3.3 comes out.
HoyoVerse dropped a trailer yesterday for the Genius Invocation TCG.
It has Diona, Fischl, and the Traveler on the thumbnail.
So it's new gameplay trailer.
Let's play Genius Invocation TCG.
It's a minute and a half.
I was recommended to check it out.
I guess it's pretty hype for the card game that's coming out as a permanent game mode
in the next patch.
Yeah, we're going to check this out.
I hope you guys enjoy.
We are live at my Twitch channel, twitch.tv forward slash murder of birds.
With all of that said, we are going to be starting new gameplay trailer.
Let's play Genius Invocation TCG.
Whoa, whoa, hold on.
Are we going into the cat's tail?
Oh, wait, that's inside.
Yo, Ellen just beat his ass, get up girl.
Oh my God.
Wait, wait, wait a minute.
I called this.
Hold on.
Guys, guys, I'm a ghost writer.
I literally asked for this last year.
Hold on, hold on.
Pause champ.
I got to find this.
When I did Diona's hangout last year.
No, you did not.
I'm going to find the proof.
I'm finding it right now and I'm going to show all of you.
This is my Genshin Impact playlist during the year the game released.
I did Diona's hangout on July 4th, 4th of July, 2021.
Give me one second.
So this is the video in question and this is the moment that I'm referring to.
Hold on.
I think it's right after this.
Anyway, if you want to check out the cat's tail for yourself, the entrance is just around
dude.
I wish the cat's tail.
I wish, so here's something that I really hope miHoYo does in the future.
I want to be able to go inside the, the cat's tail.
I want to, and I want to be able to go inside the adventurers guild headquarters.
I, you know what I mean?
Like we get to go inside the angel share tavern.
We get to go inside the Knights of Favonius headquarters.
We get to go into the church.
Like these are two other well-established locations in the city and I, it's always bothered
me that we never get to go in there, especially since we are a, an adventurer technically,
you know what I mean?
I'm fucking AR 57.
You tell me I can't go in the building, add it to the list, boys.
Let's go.
Let's carry on.
I manifested this.
Okay.
Everyone that's hyped for this.
You're welcome.
Oh, the gang.
Oh my God.
This is so cool.
We finally get to go inside.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see what's in there.
Oh shit.
The music.
No.
Wow.
Yo.
I'll call these a card.
Yup.
Sing show.
This is so sick.
Wow.
Welcome to the cat's tail.
Ah, what a nice surprise.
Don't tell me you came to learn genius and vocation TCG without bringing any card.
It's time to see what you are made of.
Oh my God.
Oh minute card.
I'm so excited for this game.
Do we get the first?
All of them.
Yeah.
The pretty caterpillar saw him in the trailer in the.
Live stream.
No, this music goes in the minute.
Charles and Chloe.
I'm sorry.
Chongyun as well.
You know, that was actually kind of hype.
We have an animal hypostasis card. We have guoba, osvaldo, von hafnavines. We got a bunch of animation cards. That looks sick
Wow, they really went all out on this card game. There's a catherine card as well. Wow. This looks really really good, dude
It's so fucking cool that we're in the freaking the tavern itself. Oh, we're in the cat's tail like bar itself
Yeah, i'm gonna suck at this card game too, by the way, because i'm not very good at card games
But i'm definitely down to verse the npcs and like first like a bunch of the playable characters
Look, i'm going to be able to verse sino
official
Uh sucrose
I love that collie's a card like a bunch of my favorite characters are playable cards
And the element like they basically gave everyone like a card version of an elemental burst, which is super cool
What a nice surprise. Yeah, I think that's margaret talking to learn genius invocation tcg without bringing any cards
It is time to see what you are made of god. This is so sick. The music is really good, too
Prince I wonder if we get to duel the king of games right there the car the freaking the card cat the cat card cat
Nice
Wow, that was pretty hype. They also advertised the card game. I think today's kaya's birthday as well
They advertised the card game through kaya's birthday letter and I was just like damn, bro
Y'all are down bad for this card game. Jesus christ
Yeah, I have no idea how the card game works
Like I know that there are people already talking about stuff in it
But um, I i'm just gonna wait for it to come out in game. I need to collect the cards
I need to find out like the best decks possible to build that's gonna be exciting
like I already look at people's guides for like character builds if i'm looking for inspiration or if I
Want to find the most optimal build possible
But the cards are gonna be really interesting to figure out because you know
You you're gonna need the best cards to beat the npcs
but then you're gonna need like
The actual good cards to if you when you go up against people in pvp if you care about that stuff pvp doesn't really have
Um pvp you don't get rewards or anything like that. There's like no leaderboards for it either
So like realistically speaking like there's nothing to gain from losing
I mean, there's nothing to gain really from winning other than keeping your own personal record
I guess but uh
or if you want to like do if you want to host tournaments with your friends or like if you want to do like a
Community function or something like that
But uh, yeah for me at least i'm like super super super excited to just get the cards and to just see how they work
And to go up against other playable characters like sino like fischl and characters from all over the game
So i'm really really excited for that
I would also it would also be super cool if someone literally started playing genshin for the sole purpose of building up their cards
And their deck and then play this on stream
Like I wouldn't be I wouldn't be upset if there were just like ingenious invocation tcg dedicated streamers and like content creators
I think that'd be kind of cool. I just hope that they update the game as it goes on
I think everybody should have a card in the game, too
I think every playable character should have a card. I think every mob should have a card
I think every like significant npc should have a card like they have a catherine card. They have a libin card
They should have a wagner card. They should have a
Masanori card like even cards like connected to lore like an enjo card
Alumine card, that'd be kind of cool depends on like the the function of the card itself. That would be really really hype
It would be cool if they updated the card system every time a new character comes out
So scaramouche and farzen are coming out on 3.3
It'd be cool if every character also came with a card added to like the roster of cards in the shop
I think that would be really neat
It really just depends it depends on how they want to how far they want to take this card game or if what we see
Is what we'll ever get but they they rotate spiral abyss like spiral abyss isn't the same that it was when it initially came out
So while spiral abyss hasn't changed
Fundamentally, it does go through cycles and changes
So I hope I hope that it does with the card game as well because a lot of people are really hyped for this
I'm not hyped from like a meta or like a competitive standpoint, but that does breed more
Interest for the general community and i'm excited to just see
How far people take the card game how serious they take it because i'm a big fan of like competitive scenes and stuff like that
And if it's genshin, you know, i'll definitely check it out. But uh, yeah, this was pretty awesome. This is pretty great
We actually get to go into the uh, the uh, the we actually get to go inside the cat's tail bar
So that gives me hope that in the far flung future we'll actually be able to go into the adventurers guild
headquarters be at the one in monstad or maybe we'll go to the official one in
Snejnaja since that is where the adventurers guild is originally hosted and and founded but um, but yeah
That's gonna do it for this video. Thank you guys all so much for watching
I know it's a pretty lengthy video for such a short trailer, but uh, we're kind of at the tail end of content right now
I I still have nahita's quest to do i'm gonna be doing that tomorrow. I have character lore to read
We're going to be going through the picture event today. So I really appreciate all the support
Thank you guys again for watching leave your thoughts in the comment section down below
And we will see you all in the next one. Take care.